(边城)
"Edge City"
我要再放一根下去
Another one coming down
先等一下
Hang on
摩登大圣
THE MASK
我弄到了...
I got those...
你要的音乐会票
concert tickets you wanted
真的呀？
You're kidding!
是周五晚的？
For Friday night?
太棒了，史丹利
Stanley, this is great
我几点去接你？
What time do I pick you up?
有个小状况
Here's the thing
我的好友来了
她想去得要命
My best girlfriend is here
and she'd die to go to this...
能不能帮她弄一张？
so could we get an extra ticket
for her?
票卖光了，  买不到了
They're sold out. That means
there's no more
但我不能把她丢在家里
I can't let her sit home all alone
我看这样吧
I'll tell you what
你跟她去听
Go with your friend
这怎么行呢
I couldn't do that
没关系啦
No, come on
史丹利，你真是盖世
Stanley, you are the nicest guy
真的，史丹利
Really, you are
查理，你说对不对？
顶尖好人
- Isn't he the nicest guy?
- The best
她的脸皮比牛皮还厚
That was the most sickening display
恶心透顶
我不同意
- I've ever seen.
- I disagree
我跟她慢慢磨
I'm wearing her down
老兄，你该换换口味了
Buddy, you need a little
change of pace
今晚我带你去猎艳
Tonight, I'll take you
on a love safari
深入都市丛林最黑暗之心
Deep into the darkest heart
of the urban jungle
说来听听，酋长
Tell me more, bwana
椰鼓夜总会
全城最红的新场子
The Coco Bongo CIub.
Hottest new joint in town
只有摩登凯子才准入场
Only the cr me de la cr me
need apply
我们算老几？
你别漏气了
- How do we get in?
- Are you kidding?
交给我，你就安啦
Leave it to me.
Trust me, buddy
我们要红遍全城
This will be the perfect...
就在今夜
night on the town
且慢
Hold the phone
绝色美女在三点钟方向
Killer at three o'clock
你留守后方好好观察
Stand back and observe
请问在哪办开户？
Where do I open an account?
新开户就在这里
New accounts,right here
你真幸运，我正要出差
You're Iucky, I was on my way out--
帮我拿一下
Hold this for me, please?
要我拿一辈子都行
I'll hold anything you want
你帮我办，好吗？
Can you help me?
那么？
So...
你想开哪种户头？
what kind of account do you want?
我也不确定
我对理财最外行
Well, I'm not sure exactly. I'm
just terrible with things like that
你的领带帅毙了
That's an interesting tie, Mister...
在下史丹利伊卜吉
Ipkiss, Stanley Ipkiss
幸会，我叫婷娜
Tina Carlyle, it's a pleasure
荣幸之至
Pleasure's all mine
可以用吗？
May I?
用什么？
What?
我像落汤鸡
I'm such a mess
请用
Oh, of course
本来就是给人用的
That's what they're there for
见到你的领带
As I was saying, that tie...
使我想起那种心理测验
“墨渍测验”
reminds me of those,
what do you call it, ink blot tests
罗夏发明的
对
- A Rorschach test.
- Right
它看起来像...
It sort of looks like...
骑无鞍马的妙龄女
a young woman riding bareback
例如那
Sort of...
裸体的伯爵夫人
Lady Godiva or something
是的
Of course
你自己觉得呢？
What do you see, Mr. Ipkiss?
我不知道
I don't know
颜色很亮丽
Bright colors...
带给人权力感
It's a power tie
使人感觉...
Supposed to make you feel...
更够力
powerful
你够力吗？
Does it work?
好了，关于开户的事
Now, how about that account?
我们有
We have...
好几种户头
several different plans
活期
Savings
支票
Checking
活期加支票
Savings and checking
活期加定存
Savings and CD's
支票加定存
Checking and CD's
活期加支票、定存
国库券
Savings, checking and CD's.
T-Bills
或干脆把钱挖洞藏起来
Or we can throw your money
in a big mattress
你填一些表格吧
Now, I have some forms
for you to fill out
很好，再向右一点点
That's it, sweetheart.
Now just a little bit to the right
你们小声一点
Keep it down back there
是的
We'll try
你觉得如何？
格局还可以，但...
- What do you think?
- Layout's not bad. But...
警报器非常棘手
the motion detectors are a pain
你搞得定吗？
But you can pulI this off, right?
我办事，你放心
You talking to the Doctor
但我有个疑问
I do have one question
你说
Which is?
尼哥有什么意见？
What's Niko have to say about this?
没意见
Nothing
他不搞抢银行
你多用些脑筋
- This isn't his grift.
- Get real, man
他什么都搞
Everything is his grift
你是他的，夜总会也是
他的势力遍及全城
He owns you, he owns this cIub,
he owns this whole stinking town
现在不同了
Things change
你惹他，只有死路一条
You mess with Niko, you end up
taking a dirt nap
不用脑筋的是他
He's the only one who's napping...
我要狠狠将他唤醒
and I'm about to give him
a serious wake-up call
但我们需要钱
But we need cash...
所以先抢银行
so first we take the bank...
再做掉尼哥
then we take Niko...
然后我们就自由了
and then, my friend,
school is out
全城任我们放肆猖狂
And this whole city is our playground
走路不长眼睛！
Bub, watch where you're going!
马上来
Hang on, hang on!
你急着去投胎呀
Don't get your panties in a twist
这是什么歪哥？
What the hell is it?
我不知道
I don't know...
值七百元就对了
about seven hundred bucks, eh?
有何贵干，朋友？
Now, what can I do for you, bub?
我来领我的喜美
I'm here for the Civic
刹车鼓损坏
整组传动要换
The brake drums are shot
and you need a new transmission
什么？
What?!
我只是来换机油
All I wanted was an oil change
我们及早发现问题
算你狗命够大
Lucky we caught these problems
before they caused serious trouble
签名，用力写
Sign right here, and press down hard
没写价钱
我们会写
- There's no price.
- There will be
我今晚要用车呀
I've no car.
I need a car tonight
把专车借给他
Bring around the loaner
专车？
The loaner?
古董名车
It's a classic
查理，我死党史丹利伊卜吉
Gals, meet my buddy Stanley Ipkiss
银行巨子
Humungo in the banking business
黑白讲
咱们进去吧
- Not really.
- Let's get in this joint
大块头，你好吗？
How you doing, buddy?
我是查理呀
你好
- It's Charlie!
- How you doing?
近来可好？
好久不见
- How you doing, my friend?
- Long time no see
真是幸会
Good to see you
娘儿们，走吧
Come on, gals
咱们里面见
See you on the inside
这是误会
This is a mistake
好大狗胆，竟敢跨越绳子
You crossed the rope.
Never cross the rope
我朋友在里面
扔出去
- My friends are inside.
- Lose him
这怎么可以
This isn't fair
小心，我有血友病
Watch it, I'm a bleeder
放下来
否则别想赚我的钱
Put me down now, or I am
never coming back here
衰到家了
Jeez
伊卜吉先生
Mr. Ipkiss!
嗨
Hi
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我？
Me?
我好得很
I'm great.
好得不得了
Really good
我从未这么开心过
I never felt better, really
我只是...
I'm just...
出来透透气
catching some air
先生，你的车
Your car, sir
这不是我的车
That's not my car
是它没错
It matches the ticket
好吧
AIright...
给我就开
I'll take it
但我非常不满意！
But I am very angry!
你相信吗？
Believe this?
我开保时捷来的
You drive in in a Porsche...
先生
Hey, Mister!
撑住呀
Hold on!
我会心肺复苏术
I know CPR!
喂！你！
Hey, you!
你在下面干什么？
What are you doing down there?
我正在找...
I'm just looking for...
我的面具
my mask!
找到了
I got it
你知道现在几点了？
Do you have any idea what time it is?
我真的不知道
Actually, no
我新铺的地毯！
My new carpet!
伊卜吉，我要扣你的押金
Well ,this is coming right out
of your security deposit
我告诉你...
You know...
什么？
What?
没什么
Nothing
空心大老倌，没出息！
Well, that's what you are, Ipkiss,
a big nothing
你这冷血的母僵尸！
Aren't you due at the lab
to get your bolts tightened?
我应该骂给她听见
I should have said that
你好呀
Hey, you
麦乐
Milo!
不许乱跳
要遵守狗民生活须知
No jumping up allowed.
It's against doggie ordinance
你想干什么？
What do you want?
要我掷飞盘？
You want me to throw that?
我累毙了
I'm very tired
我只丢一次
I'll throw it one time
你咬着我怎么丢
I won't throw it with you
attached to it
好了吗？
You ready?
接住
Get it
伊卜吉
Ipkiss!
小声一点！
Turn down those cartoons!
好啦，平曼太太
AIright, Mrs. Peenman!
您说人人都戴着面具！
Dr. Neuman, you say that everybody
wears a mask?
没错
That's correct
戴面具是一种比喻
We all wear masks,
metaphorically speaking
我们压抑本我的深层欲望
We suppress the id,
our darkest desires...
装出社会能接受的形象
and adopt a more socially
acceptable image
纽曼博士大作
“我们的面具”
The book is "The Masks We Wear"
by Dr. Arthur Neuman
谢谢您接受访问
Thank you for being here
你是怎么了？
What's the matter with you?
怎么了？
What is it?
你在找什么？
What are you looking for?
你喜欢这玩意？
You like this thing? You like it?
我们的面具
"The Masks We Wear"
没错
"That's correct
戴面具是一种比喻
We all wear masks,
metaphorically speaking"
酷毙了！
Yeah, right
我现在要出征
Smoking!
派对时间到了
It's party time
派-对
P-A-R-T-Y
为什么？因为我想要
Why? Because I gotta
(管理经理)
MANAGER
(请轻声)
QUIET PLEASE
Snooze!
我成了路上的扁尸
Look, ma, I'm road kill!
别挡路！
他想较量一下
- Get out of the road!
- I think he wants to communicate
(轻轻按我)
squeeze me gently
先生
Hey, mister...
现在几点？
you got the time?
大草包，我告诉你吧
As a matter of fact, I do, Cubbie!
你瞧瞧
Look at that!
你该把鼻子当喇叭按
Time to honk your nose and pulI
your underwear over your head
上呀
Come on!
放马过来，别害羞
Step right up here, don't be shy!
皮衣混混
Nobody likes...
最惹人厌
a bashful leather head
快呀！
Move it!
我第一个戏法
For my first trick...
要献给你
I'll do something for you, son
长颈鹿给你
一边凉快去，别烦我
We have a giraffe. There you go, son.
Now get out of here, you bother me
现在...
Now...
抱歉，掏错口袋
Sorry, wrong pocket
给你的是...
For you...
用身体语言吧
a little body English
法国贵宾犬
A French poodle
它有狂犬病，必须安乐死
The dog was rabid, had to put it down
压轴的，是我的最爱
At last but not least, my favorite
机关枪一支
A Tommy gun
真想不到
This is incredible
有了一身特异功能
With these powers I could be...
狗熊都能变英雄
a superhero
挑战犯罪，保护无辜
I'd fight crime,
protect the innocent...
维护世界和平
work for world peace
但首先
But first...
去报仇
RIPLEY'S AUTO FINISHING
做好心理准备
Hold onto your Iug nuts...
接受彻底翻修吧
it's time for an overhaul
这是一场梦
It was a dream
一场怪梦
我该戒掉卡通了
I must lay off the cartoons
我是凯拉威分队长
你知道昨晚的骚动吗？
Lt. Kellaway. You know anything
about the disturbance last night?
骚动？
Disturbance?
歹徒闯入，攻击平曼太太
Some prowler broke in
and attacked Mrs. Peenman
攻击？
Attacked?
你都没听见？
You didn't hear anything?
她在你门外
发射好几枚霰弹
She unloaded a couple of rounds
of buckshot 5 feet from here
看地上
Look at the floor
他把钟放下，跳出窗外
He put that right in my floor,
then he jumped out...
你记下来没有？
the window. Officer,
are you writing notes?
这真是...
This is...
诡异
impossible
真有其事
你的睡衣才诡异
Those pyjamas are impossible.
This happened
我
See, I have...
内耳有问题
an inner ear problem
有时候全聋
真的吗？
- Sometimes I can't hear anything.
- Is that so?
名片给你.你若想起昨晚的事
Here's my card. If you recall
anything unusual about last night...
只要记起来，就通知我
anything at all, call me
没问题，谢谢
You bet. Thank you
祝你好运
And good Iuck...
顺利破案
cracking the case
天哪，迟到了
Oh, my God, I'm late!
钥匙呢
Keys, keys...
钥匙在哪儿？
Where's the keys?
讨厌
Damn
麦乐，去找钥匙
Get the keys
叨给我
Find them
去找钥匙呀
Get the keys
晚得太离谱了
I am so late
好狗儿
Good boy
给我吧
松口呀
Come on, Milo. Give them to me.
Drop it
找肛门医生待命
I want a proctologist standing by
找第一把肛门交椅
The best one you can find
我是记者，请问案情？
Can you tell me what happened?
我说了你会乱写
好像是黑道仇杀
- No, you can quote me.
- Looks like some Mob tactic
她已经破案了呢
把闲杂人等赶走
She broke the case. Come on,
get these rubbernecks out of here
昨晚你在哪儿？
找你找破了头
Where were you last night?
We looked all over for you
你有去臭水沟里找吗？
Did you happen to look outside,
in the gutter?
你有没有看报？
Did you check the paper?
你的马子上了头版
Your girlfriend got a great review
“肉弹爆破椰鼓”
Bombshell Explodes at Coco Bongo
迟到五十分
如同偷我的薪水
You're 50 minutes late.
That's like stealing
对不起，以后不敢了
我真是窝囊废
I'm sorry, Mr. Dickey. It'll never
happen again. I've been a jerk
你如果少看些裸女
If you weren't busy oogling
girlie pictures...
就能多办些公事
you might get some work done
她可能成为史丹利的客户
Sir. She's a perspective
client of Stanley's
真的吗？
Really?
如果她再光临
The next time she comes in...
请她到我办公室
send her to my office
没问题
You bet
但愿我爸是银行老板
Gee, I wish "my" daddy
owned a bank
我就能跟他一样臭屁
Then I could be a rich
little creep too
她还会来吗？
You think she'll ever come back?
别提她了.你听我的话
Oh, man, forget her. Listen to me
她那种妞心中想的就是钓凯子
Girls like her always look for
the BBD: Bigger Better Deal
你不了解她
You don't know that
她是艺术家，她.
She's an artist. She's...
感觉敏锐
忘掉她吧
- sensitive.
- Forget her
她会扯烂你的心
打成果汁喝
She'll rip out your heart,
put it in a blender and hit "frappe"
你需要的是单纯的那一型
You don't need her.
You need somebody down to earth
正派的女子
Somebody with some integrity.
Somebody with...
有着一头红发
red hair...
噘着丰满的唇
fulI, pouting lips...
白衫，绿外套
a white blouse, green jacket...
戴识别证
and a name tag
这范围太小了
You really narrowed it down
可惜被我包了
Too bad she's already taken
你好，请问有何贵干？
Hello there, may I be of assistance?
你是史丹利伊卜吉？
Stanley Ipkiss?
我叫佩姬，论坛报来的
Hi! I'm Peggy Brandt
from the Tribune
我没续订你的报是因为
I canceled my subscription because
they kept stealing--
我是有事问你才来的
No, actually, I want to ask you
a few questions
真的吗？什么事？
Really? About what?
你是那修车厂的客户吗？
Ripley Auto Finishing.
You're a customer, aren't you?
我？不是
Me?
我根本没车
I don't even have a car
因为车辆会污染环境
You know, 'cause they pollute
你有一辆八九年的喜美？
You don't own an '89 Civic?
你说那一辆呀
Oh, that car, yeah
我想起来了
It's coming back to me
请问芳名？
Miss... What was your name?
佩姬布兰
Peggy Brandt
且慢
Wait a minute
你是佩姬布兰？
Peggy Brandt?
那位专栏作家？
Of "Ask Peggy"?
没错
That's right
去年你登出我的信
You printed one of my letters
last year
“好男人永难出头”
Remember? "Nice Guys Finish Last."
你就是那位好男人？
You're Mister Nice Guy?
无数读者写信到报社问你
Do you realize how much mail
we got about that letter?
几百位女子想找你这种人
100's of women are looking
for a guy like you
真的吗？
Really?
你知道好男人
有多难找吗？
You know how hard it is to find
a decent man in this town?
多数男人都是大色鬼
Most think monogamy is a kind of wood
你为何采访这案子？
Why are you covering this story?
写专栏酬劳低，快饿死了
Because "Dear Peggy" pays dick.
I'm starving to death
我想当真正的记者
I'm looking to become a real reporter
你在修车厂
有看到可疑的事吗？
When you were at Ripley Auto
did you see anything suspicious?
任何怪事？
Anything?
我不会给你惹麻烦
I won't make trouble for you
我只要查明真相
I just want the truth
但愿我知道真相
我真的希望
God, I wish I knew the truth.
You know, I really do
如果你想起来
If you think of anything...
就通知我
this is my number
这支电话...
This is my...
是我的专线
you know, personal number
真的有几百位女子
想找我？
100's of women are looking
for a guy like me?
当然了
Sure
包括我在内
I'm one of them
一百二十码
120 yards
你好，多利安
Hello, Dorian
感谢你光临
Thanks for dropping by
下次先打电话
别劳动你的狗腿子
Next time, call.
Leave the delivery boys at home
今天早上
The cops...
警察想查封夜总会
tried to shut the cIub
down this morning
警方说你用它掩饰犯罪
They say you've been using the place
to run your own small-time scams
当我听到此事
When I hear things like that...
我开始分心了
I start losing my concentration
这一杆...
My game...
万一打烂了
it goes straight to hell
你也会被打烂
You could too
二0五码
205 yards
我受够你了
I'm fed up with you...
但.
but....
我法外施恩
I'll cut you a break
给你一周滚出城
One week to get out of town
如果你不滚
After that...
我就用铁杆敲你脑袋
I'll use your empty little skulI
to break in my new nine iron
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
先生，你的车
Your car, sir
见到你就没事了
I am now
婷娜，别这样
Tina, come on
别这样
You can't
痒死了
Go on
春梦醒得真快
I don't believe it
我太痴心了
Stupid
她会爱我才怪
She would never...
不行
No way!
等一下，蜜糖
Hold on, Sugar
大爷今夜想吃甜食
Daddy's got a sweet tooth tonight
打遍天下无敌手
Somebody,stop me
没钱就别想耍帅
Can't make the scene
if you don't have the green
我最好去捞一票
I better make a little stop
(边城电力公司)
EDGE CITY POWER
"SERVICE WORTH WAITING FOR"
怎样了，傅立兹？
How's it going, Freeze?
看来一帆风顺
It's looking good here
你们要靠自己了
我必须下楼让人看见
You're on your own. I must
go downstairs, make sure I'm seen
你去吧
Do it
傅立兹要出马了
The doctor is about to operate
抱歉，各位
吃多少，拿多少
Sorry, fellas. Waste not, want not
条子！
Cops!
不在名单上，就不准入内
Not on the list, not in the cIub
大家好
How do?
你在名单上吗？
You on the list?
不，但你想必认识我朋友
No, but I believe my friends are.
Perhaps you know them?
蒋中正，孙中山
Franklin, Grant...
就是钞票啦
and Jackson
谁都不许进来！
That's it! No one gets in
本店最美艳的花朵
Now we present the most beautiful
flower of the Congo Bongo...
婷娜小姐
Miss Tina Carlyle
美呆了
Beautiful
Love makes me treat you...
The way that I do
Gee, baby...
ain't I good to you
There's nothing too good...
for a boy that's so true
Gee, baby, ain't I good to you
I bought you a fur coat
for Christmas
A diamond ring...
a Cadillac car...
And everything
Love makes me treat you...
the way that I do
Gee, baby, ain't I good to you
Love makes me treat you...
the way that I do
Gee, baby, ain't I good to you
There's nothing too good...
for a man so true
Gee,baby, ain't I good to you
I know how to make a man happy
I'll treat you right
你来干什么？
大势不妙
- Why are you here?
- There's trouble
最好上楼说
You better come upstairs
我们走
Come on, let's go
They got me paying taxes...
for what I gave to you
Gee, baby, ain't I good to you
咱们来大闹天宫！
Let's rock this joint
乐歪了！
Smoking
怎么回事？
What happened?
有人抢先一步
Someone hit the joint before us
来
Get that, Doc
哈一管
Suck on that
天嫉英才呀
Son of a bitch!
是谁干的？
Who did this, man?
是谁？
Who?!
他
Him!
就是他
That's the guy
婷娜的舞伴？
The guy dancing with Tina?
他死定了
He's dead meat
来
Come on
马上给我清场
I want this place cleared now
打烊了，快走
不滚就试试看
CIub's closed. Move it!
You think I'm joking? Come on, move it!
派对结束了，走吧！
Party's over, let's go!
婷娜，你走开
Get out of here
滚一边去！
Get lost!
摩登舞王，你听着
Okay, Twinkle Toes
你马上告诉我钱在哪？
Where is my money, tell me now
你买国库券领利息
You've got 17.5% in T-bills
amortized over the fiscal year
还买股票和债券
8% in stocks and bonds
除以国民生产毛额
Carry the 9, divide by the GNP...
还好，你的葬礼花圈免税
Fortunately, funeral bouquets
are deductible
干掉这活宝
Ice this deadbeat
干掉他！
Shoot him!
谢谢
Thanks
你打中我了
You got me, partner
抱紧我
Hold me close,Red
我眼前一片黑
It's getting dark
请阿姨别忘带老黄狗散步
Tell Auntie Em to let OId Yeller out
耶诞节我不回家过了
Tell Tiny Tim I won't be coming home
this Christmas
乱世佳人，其实我受你
Tell Scarlet I do give a damn
失礼了
Pardon me
感谢捧场
Thank you
观众爱我
You love me
你们真的爱我
You really love me
你别想溜
You're not going anywhere
枪放下
Drop it, Tyrel!
放下
Drop it
有搜索票吗？还是想喝酒？
You got a warrant?
Or did you come for a nightcap?
我手上有合理根据
What I got is probable cause
你的手下抢银行
Your boys knocked over Edge City Bank
别乱摸，好痒
Easy. You're giving me a woody
其中一人戴着大绿面具
And one was wearing a big,
green mask
你难得说对一次
For once, you're right
但他不是我手下
Except it wasn't one of my boys
你该确实查清楚才说
Maybe if you tried a little
actual police work...
铐住他
Cuff him
分队长，楼上有尸体
他是抢匪
We got a stiff upstairs.
It's a guy from the heist
请你那高薪律师来
Call that high-priced
lawyer of yours
咱们去警局聊聊
We'll go downtown for a chat
带走！
Get him out of here
伊卜吉，我知道你在家
I know you're in there
我是警察
Police!
开门
Open up!
妈祖娘娘呀
Oh, my God
我知道你在里面
I know you're in there!
开门
Open up!
我敲得手起水泡了
Come on, I'm getting blisters
on my fingers
不可以
Stop it
别这样，我来了
I'm coming, okay
马上就来
I'll be right there
快一点
Let's go, move it!
好啦
AIright!
你好，分队长
Hi, Lieutenant
现在我不方便
This isn't the best time right now.
I just--
那请进吧！
Won't you come in?
你昨晚在哪里？
Where were you last night?
差不多都在家
Here, mostly
出了事吗？
Something wrong?
你对面具怪客了解多少？
What do you know about The Mask?
面具怪客？
"Mask?"
别给我装蒜
Don't insult my intelligence
他抢你的银行
我在椰鼓找到碎布
He robs the bank you work in,
then I find this in the Coco Bongo
这种骚睡衣只有你才有
There can't be 2 idiots
with these pajamas
我想看看你的睡衣
May I see those pajamas?
睡衣！
Those pajamas?
那些睡衣...
Those pajamas...
被偷了
were stolen
睡衣会被人偷？
Somebody stole your pajamas?
这个城市有够堕落的
What is this city coming to...
男人的睡衣都有人偷
when a man's pajama drawer is
no longer safe!
你看他
Look at that guy
但愿我的员工有这么勤快
彼此彼此
- Nobody's that fast at my bank.
- I'll say
那橡皮面具真不赖
That's one hell of a rubber mask
化验室怎么说？
Lab reports?
钞票上有指纹，但不是多利安手下
We got fingerprints from currency,
but nothing matches Tyrel's men
面具怪客比他们快
He beat them to the punch
查银行员工档案，核对伊卜吉的指纹
Get the bank employee files and run
down the prints on a guy named Ipkiss
你认为有内贼？
You figure it was an inside job?
找到指纹
我就能关他一辈子
I need some prints to lock
this whack job up till doomsday
我悬赏五万元
50 grand...
看谁比条子
先找到面具怪客
to whoever finds that green bastard
before the cops
你们把话放出去
I want you to get the word out
to every street hustler...
传给边城每个混混和无赖
every low life in this town.
Understand?
明天把他抓来，要活的
I want him here tomorrow, alive
你们还等什么？
You still here?
快去干活！
Come on, let's go
你看什么？
What are you looking at?
你
You
乱掉方寸了
You're losing it
我什么都没掉
I'm not losing anything...
我只想甩掉一些累赘
except maybe some extra baggage
什么意思？
What's that mean?
昨晚他吻你，你没有反抗
You didn't fight much last night
when that freak kissed you
我反抗也没用呀
Did it look like I had much
of a choice?
不见得吧
Maybe you did...
也许是没用，反正天知道
maybe you didn't. Who knows, right?
我告诉你
I'll tell you one thing
谁惹毛我，我就找谁算帐
It's going to be payback for anybody
who crosses me
银行出事
你还迟到一小时
We have a crisis here and you
stroll in an hour late?
我受够你这没路用的...
If I must put up with--
滚你的，小金牛！
Back off, monkey boy...
小心我向你老爸告状
or I'll tell your dad you treat
this place like your piggy bank
或是通知国税局
Or we should call the IRS...
请你去调查局度假！
and arrange a vacation for you
at CIub Fed?
走着瞧
That'll be all
大圣人呀
Genius
你令我乐到心坎里
That was genius. Buddy, I have chills
你今天嗑了什么魔药？
God! What side of whose bed
did you wake up on, man?
我也不清楚
I'm not sure
我最近不大像自己
I haven't exactly been myself lately
你的气色不佳
You don't look real fabulous
真的吗？
Really, do I look bad?
安啦，这会使你恢复神采
Don't worry. This'll put the color
back in your cheeks
椰鼓办慈善舞会，周六晚
2 tickets to the charity ball
at the Coco Bongo CIub, Saturday
大人物都将到场
Anybody who's anybody will be there
陪我去吧？
Want to be my date?
先等一下
Wait just a minute
你怎么来了？
我来向你道谢
- Why are you here?
- I wanted to thank you
我没钱开户了
I don't have much to open an account
with anymore
你在夜总会很红呀
What about the cIub?
You were doing great
别为我操心，没事的
It's not your problem.
I'll be okay
跟我来
Come here
你不只是来看我吧？
You didn't stop by just to see me,
did you?
没关系，告诉我
It's okay, tell me
那个抢银行的人
The guy they say robbed this place...
面具怪客？
他去过夜总会
- The Mask?
- I think he was at the cIub
真的？
Really?
听说他长得...
They say he's pretty...
有够怪异
weird looking
不过...
Yeah, but...
他是舞林豪杰
you should see him dance
他到底是何方神圣？
Did anyone find out who he is?
你有兴趣吗？
Why, you interested?
我只是好奇
Just curious, I guess
我该走了
I better be going
谢谢你一番心意
Thanks for everything
你想再见到他，对不对？
You'd like to see him again?
那就麻烦你了
I wouldn't mind
我认识他
I know him, you know
真的？
You do?
我们是大学同窗
We're old college buddies,
him and me
你提到他的舞技
It's funny you mention
he dances because...
有些舞步是我教他的
I taught him a couple of
dance moves myself
我今晚能见到他吗？
Think you could have him
meet me tonight?
我想办法
Maybe I could work something out
在公园好吗？
日落时分
- How about at Landfill Park?
- Sunset
太好了
- Perfect.
- Super
谢了，你真是大好人
Thanks, Stanley.
You really are a nice guy
这玩意很有意思
This is an interesting place
像四、五世纪的北欧面具
Looks like fourth-
or fifth-century Scandinavian
可能是北欧的一位夜神
也许是洛基
Possibly a representation of one
of the Norse night gods, maybe Loki
洛基？
Loki?
洛基是谁？
Who is Loki?
北欧的恶作剧之神
The Norse god of mischief
他是闯祸大王
天父将他永远逐出天宫
Supposedly he caused such trouble that
Odin banished him from Valhalla forever
也许他被贬到面具里
Then he could have banished him
into that mask
那都是神话
I'm talking about mythology,
Mr. Ipkiss
这只是一块木头
This is a piece of wood
但你的书...
but your book...!
我的书是拿面具做比喻
My book is about
masks as a metaphor
不是照字面去解释
A metaphor,not to be taken literally
你患了轻微的妄想症
You suffer from a mild delusion
好吧
AIright
我证明给你看
I'll prove it to you
但后果我不负责
But I am not responsible
for the consequences
坐下来欣赏吧，大专家
Just sit back and enjoy the ride,
Mr. Expert
有啥好怕的，请便
You don't scare me.
Go right ahead
再见
See you
洛基是夜神
也许晚上才有效
You said Loki was a night god.
Maybe it works at night
先生，我警告你
我不亲自辅导重症患者
I should warn you that I don't work
personally with really sick people
你该去找私人机构
There are private institutions
for those things
如果你想入院，我今晚就能帮你安排
I can arrange for a safe environment
for you tonight, if you want
我一定要见婷娜
I must see Tina
但我该怎么办？
But what can I do?
以原来面貌去？
Do I go as myself...
或是戴上面具？
or The Mask?
我说完，你就离开好吗？
If I tell you, you promise
to leave my office right now?
本貌
Go as yourself...
和面具一起去
and as The Mask
他们是一体的
都是大好人
Because they are both
one and the same beautiful person
指纹证实是伊卜吉的
Got the cross-check on
the fingerprints. It's Ipkiss
我正盯着他
I'm looking at him
叫霹雳小组待命
Keep the SWAT team standing by
若他真那么难缠
就得闹一夜
If he's half as bad as they say,
we'll have a fulI dance card
有泡菜酱吗？
Pickle relish?
上车
我还点了洋葱圈
- Get in the car.
- But I ordered onion rings
LANDFILL PARK
史丹利，你怎么来了？
What are you doing here?
我只是路过来确定你们见到面
I wanted to make sure that you
2 got together all right
你真好
That's nice
我很少来这里
I hardly ever stop by here
真想不到这里曾是...
It's hard to believe it was...
垃圾场
a garbage heap
日落时分真美
It's really beautiful
right around sunset
沼气加深了天色
The methane emissions
really pick up the colors
满天的...
All those...
姹绿嫣红
pinks and greens
他随时会到，我走了
My friend will be along here
any minute. I better go
等等，史丹利
Stanley, wait
你好，心肝儿
Hello, cherie
我们重逢了
We meet again!
这是命运吗？
Is it fate?
是否星辰上面写着
Is it meant to be?
It is written in the stars...
我们注定要相好？
that we are destined to fraternize?
我愿意这样想
I'd like to think so
吻我，我就奉献给你
Kiss me, my dear, and I will reveal
my croissant
我带你同奔极乐
我带你共浴瑶池
I will spread your p t . I will dip
my ladle in your vichyssoise
她可真怕羞
She's so coy
我喜欢
I love it
我们的爱像红红的玫瑰
Our love is like a red, red rose
令我兴奋莫名
And I am a little thorny
我爱慕你
Je t'adore! Je t'adore!
说法文比较不恶心
Shoot the window. I don't care!
我是凯拉威，加派人手来
This is Kellaway.
I need back-up
抽烟吗？不抽？
Cigarette?
我好像拿破仑
Now, like Napoleon...
分散敌军，各个击破
I will divide and conquer
我是警察！
Police!
电灯泡
Merde
“别动”
Freeze
手举起来
Put your hands up
你不是叫我“结冻”？
But you told me to freeze
好啦，化冻
AIright, alright, unfreeze
你被捕了
You're under arrest
不是我干的
It wasn't me
是“绝命追杀令”那独臂人
It was the one-armed man
好吧，我招了
AIright, I confess
是我干的，我非常得意
I did it, you hear?
And I'm glad, glad, I tell you!
警伯，他们会把我怎样？
What are they going to do to me, Sarge?
What are they going to do?
抱歉，不关我的事
Sorry, son, that's not my department
搜身
Search him
应该拍下来告你们刑求
Where's a camcorder when you need one?
今晚搞不完了
老婆会宰了我
It's going to be a long night.
My wife'll kill me
怎么了？
伊卜吉在公园被捕
- What is it?
- Cops got Ipkiss at Landfill Park
让我去采访这案子
你回家陪老婆
Let me cover it. I need this story.
You go home to Claire
可是上面说...
I don't know. Ramsey said--
我去跟上面说
I will take care of Ramsey
感激不尽，算我欠你
Thanks a million, I owe you one
超大墨镜
Really big sunglasses, nerf ball...
单车喇叭
Bike horn...
小嘴鲈鱼
Small-mouthed bass...
bowling pin...
捕鼠器
mouse-trap...
橡皮鸡
rubber chicken...
吃这个也痒，吃那个也痒
- Little to the left. That's it.
- I don't know
玩具眼珠
Funny eyeball glasses...
没看过这种眼镜
I've never seen those in my life
火箭筒
我有执照的
- bazooka.
- I have a permit for that
凯拉威夫人玉照
- Picture of Kellaway's wife...
- What?
“爱人，我等你”
CalL ME LOVER!
你勾引我老婆！
Margaret! Son of a bitch!
我还以为你幽默
I figured you had a sense of humor
毕竟...夫妻一场嘛
you married her!
这够痛了吧
That's got to hurt
抓住他
Get him!
伊卜吉，把手举起来
It's over. Raise your hands...
否则开火
or we'll fire
开枪
Hit it!
人家叫我古巴皮
我是伦巴舞皇帝
They call me Cuban Pete
I'm the king of the rumba beat
当我摇起响葫芦
When I play the maracas
我就劈哩啪啦碰
I go chick-chicky boom
是的，吾乃古巴皮
Yes, I'm Cuban Pete
人间就属我最皮
I'm the craze of my street
当我跳起舞，劈哩啪啦碰
When I start to dance everything goes
Chick-chicky boom, chick-chicky boom
妞儿唱歌...
The seoritas sing...
又跳舞
and they swing
跳得又帅又惹火
It's very nice
跳得人心痒难熬
FulI of spice
她们唱歌又跳舞 跳的真不错
They dance and bring a happy ring
Never a care
从早到晚，笙歌不辍
Singing a song
All the day long
若你喜欢这节奏
就来学我古巴皮
If you like the beat
Take a lesson from Cuban Pete
脸贴着脸黏巴达
I'll teach you to
chick-chicky boom
他这男人真内向
He's a modest guy
不过却是万人迷
AIthough he's the hottest guy
哈瓦那的万人迷
In Havana
是的，小姐，我知道
Si, senorita, I know...
that when I chicky boom
我是又帅又惹火
It's very nice
so fulI of spice
我把手放你身上
I place my hand on your hip
让你赏我几耳光
And if you will give me your hand
那么你我就起舞
Then we shall try
Just you and I
热情有劲
闭嘴，拉我一把
- Not bad.
- Shut up and help me down
我会教你跳这支舞
I'll teach you to chick-chicky boom
Chick-chicky boom
再跳就轰掉你的狗头
Dance and I'll blow your brains out
枪给我
Give me that thing
后会有期
See you!
去抓他
醒过来，别跳了！
There! Let's get him.
Snap out of it. This dance is over!
走呀，同志们
Let's go! Follow me, officers!
他在巷子里
拿着枪跟我来
He's down the alley. Follow me.
Come on. Grab your gun
史丹利，上车
Stanley, get in!
在那边
There!
再跑就开枪
Halt, or I'll shoot!
开枪呀
Shoot! Shoot!
不绑安全带会罚款
Seat belts
我没打中
I missed him
谁打得中他
Come on, we all missed him
“面具怪客抢银行”
THE MASK ROBS BANK
我看到了
I saw it
全都看到了
I saw everything
史丹利，你是怎么了？
What's happening to you, Stanley?
我发疯了
It's crazy
我无法控制自己
I'm losing control
当我戴上面具
When I put that mask on...
我就能做任何事
I can do anything
变成任何东西
Be anything
它毁灭着我
It's wrecking my life
害我过得一塌糊涂
My life is wrecked. Wrecked
这些我并不清楚
I don't know what's happening to you...
但我明白一点
but I do know this:
写信到我专栏的那人
that letter you sent my column...
他的勇气十足
that was from a guy with more guts...
心地善良
and more heart...
强过全城所有的烂男人
than any of the creeps
I've met in this city
不管那是什么面具
Whatever that mask is...
你都不需要了
you don't need it
你
You...
史丹利伊卜吉
Stanley Ipkiss...
你只需做好你自己
are already all you'll ever need to be
佩姬
Gosh, Peg...
这是你的真心话吗？
do you really mean that?
老实说...
Actually...
不见得
no
什么？
What?
你们害我
多扯二十分钟的谎
Where were you? I've been vamping
for 20 minutes
就是他？
Is this him?
五万块呢？
You got the 50 thou'?
把钱给她
Give her the money
很好
Right
他戴上面具就变成怪客
With the mask on, he turns
into that green thing
你这是干什么？
What are you doing?
抱歉，你的确是好人
但我缺钱就没房子住
Sorry. You really are a great guy,
I just can't lose my condo
在市内找房子太难了
It's so hard to find an apartment
in this city
你说过不会伤害他
You said you wouldn't hurt him!
我骗你的
I lied
告诉我
Tell me
面具有什么奇效？
How's this mask work?
我也不清楚
I don't know. You just...
你戴上就知道
put it on
老板
Boss...
保重呀
be careful, huh?
酷得歪七扭八
What a rush
你还好吗？
You okay?
我从未这么好过
I'm better than ever, you idiot
怎样处置伊卜吉？
What do we do with Ipkiss?
警方要面具
The police want the mask
就把面具怪客送警
We'll give them The Mask
最好找得到钱
The money better be here...
否则你就是夭寿怪客
or you can Ip-kiss your ass good-bye
在这里
Get over there
想不到
干练警员沿街起舞
Can't believe it. Hardened cops
dancing in the street...
在夜间新闻播出
and broadcast on the 11 o'clock news
赌城还请霹雳小组去作秀
我完了
- The SWAT team was offered Vegas.
- I'm history
队长会炒我鱿鱼
退休金泡汤
The Captain'll have my badge
for breakfast with a pension on top
这不能怪你
吉人自有天相
It's not all your fault.
Something will turn up
除非伊卜吉掉在我怀里
Sure, Ipkiss will fall
right into my lap
把他弄开！
Get him off of me!
等等
Wait!
让我解释清楚
I can explain everything
是吗？那你解释这个
You can explain everything?
Explain this!
铐起来
我为你准备了客房
Get him up! Let's go!
I got a cell for you, pal
忘了我吧
Forget about me, buddy
找一个新窝
Find a new place to live
我要关好久好久
I'll be in here for a long, long time
喂，丑八怪
You, with the face
有访客
You got a visitor
你怎么来了？
是真的吗？
- Why?
- Is it true?
你就是面具怪客
You're The Mask
别跟任何人说
Yeah, but don't tell anybody.
If I get...
只要找到好律师
a good lawyer and a deal...
我再关一万年就可以出狱
I'll be out in about 10,000 years
你来这里太危险
It's risky, coming here
你男友会不爽的
Your boyfriend might be upset
他今晚要去慈善舞会做坏事
He'll be at the charity ball tonight
他想跳黏巴达吗？
Like what? The Lambada?
别耍嘴皮了，一定要阻止他
This is serious. There must be a way
to stop him
它有什么魔力？
How does it work?
我不知道
I don't know
好像是...
It's like...
它使人最隐密的欲望成真
it brings your innermost desires
to life
若你的内心深处
If deep down inside...
略带压抑却又浪漫至情
you're a bit repressed and
hopelessly romantic...
那你就会变成
you become some sort of...
为爱痴狂的浪人
a love-crazy wild man
如果是多利安戴它呢？
And if you're like Dorian?
那大家都完了
Then we're all in big trouble
若我是你
就马上远走高飞
And if I were you,
I'd get out of town. Fast
感谢你
Thanks
谢什么？
For what?
很多事
Lots of things
你与我分享夕阳
Sharing a sunset with me
只有你把我当人看
For being the only guy who treated me
like a person, not...
而非当玩物
a party favor
感谢你一片深情
For being any kind of romantic...
虽然浪漫得无药可救
even a hopeless one
不客气
You're welcome
那晚在夜总会
That night at the cIub I knew...
我邂逅了意中人
I'd found someone special
面具怪客
The Mask
不，是面具后面的男子
It was the guy inside The Mask
就是你本人
It was you all along
小姐，时间到
Lady, time's up
拜托宽限...
Could I have just...
一分钟？
one more minute?
我要躲藏一阵子
I've got to disappear for a while now
我找到地方
会尽快通知你
Don't know where but I'll let you know
as soon as I can
救命呀
Somebody help me!
警卫
Guard, guard!
有人在巷内追杀女子
A woman's being chased in the alley
快去救她呀
She needs help
罗嗦，小声一点
Sure. Keep it down
你算什么人民保姆！
Serve and protect, man!
好孩子，来
Good boy. Come on
跳上来，会吗？
Jump up. Can you jump up?
我曾教你别乱跳
现在收回成命
Remember how I taught you not to
jump up on people? Forget that
跳上来
Come on! Get up here
上来呀
Get up. Get up here!
跳上来呀
Get up. Get up here. That's it
你是神犬，没问题
You can do it.
Come on. Come on!
用力跳
Put some effort into it!
宝贝，总算找到你了
Baby, there you are
我不大放心你
I was worried about you
你找条子告密？
我只有问伊卜吉的事
- You talk to the cops?
- Only to see what Ipkiss told them
你跟他走得太近了吧
That's right, you and Stanley.
You two are getting awfully close
他抢银行想必是你帮他
Bet you helped him with the bank job
胡说
是吗？
- That's ridiculous.
- Oh, is it?
她车上有行李
Look what I found in her car
想一个人溜吗？
Going away alone, baby?
喽罗们
Boys, I want you to...
给她找件漂亮衣服
get her something pretty to wear
今晚有宴会
We're going to a party tonight
要痛快飙一晚
We'll have one hell of a time, right?
你滚一边去
Get out of my sight
跳呀
Jump up
百尺竿头，更进一步
Get up. Come on
麦乐，拜托你跳
Come on, Milo. Jump, please
为你老子跳一个
Do it for Daddy
酷呆了
That's it!
真想不到
God, I can't believe it
我的乖孩子
Good boy. Good boy
看到那个人吗？
See that man over there?
他有钥匙
He's got keys
把钥匙弄来
Go get those keys
去偷钥匙
Go get them. Go get the keys
对了
That's it
钥匙
The key
不是起司，是钥匙
No, not the cheese, the keys
放下起司
Drop the cheese...
去偷钥匙
and get the keys
在那边
Over there, over there
乖狗儿，过来
Oh, man. Come on
我的好祖宗
Come here. Good boy. That's a good boy
把钥匙给我
Give it, give me the keys.
Give me the keys
松口啦
Come on, drop it, drop it
太阳下山了
It's sundown
好戏开锣了
It's almost time
我劝你别点烟
I wouldn't, darling
（炸药，危险）
DANGER
EXPLOSIVES
别这么早放烟火
Wouldn't want to start the
celebration early
不要动
Hold it!
我警告你
I am warning you...
你逼得我要发飙了
I am seriously stressed out here
放轻松
Easy
过来
Come on
别活得不耐烦
Don't be an idiot
这里是警察局
你不可能出得去
You're in a police station. There is no
way you'll walk out of here like this
你说得对
You're know, you're right
一点也没错
你干什么？
- Absolutely right.
- What are you doing?
咱们玩...
You'll take me out...
官兵抓强盗
as your prisoner
铐上！
Put it on! Put it on!
走
Come on
我很遗憾
- I'm really very sorry about this.
- I'm sure
你们抓错人了
You got the wrong guy
我是冤大头
It's a bum rap
要尊重人权嘛
I got my rights
你为何带走伊卜吉？
Where are you taking Ipkiss?
“枪有他”
Ixnay! Ehay's otgay an ungay
原来你倒过来讲
I get it. Pig Latin, right?
“见头回”
Eesay ouyay aterlay
来呀
Come on!
你坐好，放轻松
Sit back and relax
我要更衣赴宴
I must change for the party
“豪睹之夜”
TONIGHT, CASINO
“战火孤儿基金”
WAR ORPHANS FUND
买烟
I need cigarettes
什么牌子？
无所谓，我不抽烟
- Which brand?
- It doesn't matter, I don't smoke
但我会帮你杀掉卫生署长
But for you, I would shoot
the Surgeon General
条顿市长，可以访问您吗？
Mayor Tilton, may we have a word?
我一向
欢迎新闻界和忠心选民
I always have time for the press
and my loyal constituents
放开我，你开车太恐怖
Let me out of these cuffs,
you drive like a maniac
抱歉，怕赶不上舞会
Sorry, we're late for the ball
别假仙了，迟到大王
Alice and the rabbit'll be
disappointed
你也会讽刺了
Now you're being cynical
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是你的离职员工
I'm just an ex-employee...
我来讨你欠的薪水
who's come for his back pay
或者说来找你算帐
Or should I say payback?
杀掉他
Kill him
你上呀
Come on
各位来宾
Ladies and gentlemen...
现在起
I will be the host...
由我来主持
for the rest of the evening
拉开你的狗
Get your dog away from me
它似乎和你心心相印
Sorry, he seems to be attracted to you
人呢？情况不大妙
Where's everyone?
Something's not kosher
小心
- Exactly.
- Watch it!
对不起
Sorry
我必须把你锁在车内
I must lock you in
打开无线电
Use the radio
做什么？
请求支援呀
You know, call for back-up
or something
这很危险，你乖乖别动
This could be dangerous.
Stay here and be a good boy
你老子我要去扁人
Daddy has to go kick some ass
他嫌人生乏味
He's a dead man
趴下
Down! Get down!
我懂，轻一点
Take it easy, I got the point
轰掉它！
Blow it!
你卑鄙
Bastard
怎么了，亲爱的？
What's the matter, darling?
他们是你的大舞群
This is your big production number
做秀就是为了
And you know it's important...
“轰轰烈烈”地成名
to go out with a big bang
查理，你怎么来了？
Why are you here?
拿着枪，溜到后面去
Take this gun and start
sneaking people out the back
退后
Step back
你知道我是什么人？
你不退后就是死人
- Do you know who I am?
- A dead man if you don't step back
你难道不尊重法律和命令吗？
What about some respect?
你算什么流氓呀？
炸弹设定完毕
- What kind of thug are you?
- All set, Dorian
好极了
That's it
再过十分钟
This party's over...
舞会就完了
in 10 minutes
在这一关键时刻
This is the moment when a man...
男儿要展露本性
shows what he's really made of
枪放下
Crap
放下
Drop it
真机灵
Smart dog
老板，有不速之客
Boss, look who decided to crash
the party
多利安，你好吗？
How's it going?
带过来！
Bring him up here!
多利安，等一下
Wait! No!
没时间听你的临终请求
This is no time for last requests
我只求一吻
But all I wanted was a kiss
一个吻？
A kiss?
只是一个吻...
Just one...
最后的一吻
last kiss
定时器关不掉呀
I can't shut it off
有的是时间
There's always time...
才一个吻而已
for one last kiss
要正牌的多利安来吻
From the real Dorian
我所爱的那位
The one I used to love
他的吻举世无双
Nobody ever kissed me
like Dorian Tyrel
罗密欧呀
Romeo!
这儿快炸了
This place will blow!
你给我等着！
Just wait!
我决定了
I've decided...
我要让她含笑而终
to give her one last thrill
接住它！
Get it!
快跑，麦乐
Run, Milo!
史丹利，快呀
Stanley, hurry!
你安啦
Don't worry
已经没戏唱了
It's all over now
抓住你了
Got you
我要剥你的皮
I'll take you apart
用你的独眼享受胜利吧
I hope you can enjoy the victory
with one freaking eye!
狗儿乖乖
Good doggie
好狗儿
我赢了！
I'm winning!
我是洛基！
JACKPOT
我的老天呀！
Oh, my God!
它一定是新品种
This must be a new breed
别急
Easy, boy!
好狗儿
Good boy!
你们又没打中吗？
Did you miss me?
打中了
I guess not!
你们快扪心自问：
Now, you have to ask yourself
one question:
“我的命够硬吗？”
"Do I feel Iucky?"
怎样呀？
Well...
痞子，你们的够硬吗？
do you...
（玩具枪）
punks?
这肉丸挺辣的
That's a spicy meatball
怎样呀？
How do?
这家伙狗命真长
This guy's incorrigible
你是很有两下子啦
You were good, kid, real good...
但只要有我
你就一边凉快
but as long as I'm around
you'll be second-best
手举起来！
Police! Hands up!
条子们，逮捕这些人！
Officers, arrest those men
指挥警察真神气
I've always wanted to say that
走
Come on
枪拿来
Give me that gun
他抢了我们的珠宝
He stole all our jewelry.
Take me to headquarters...
拦住他
Stop that man!
伊卜吉，我逮到你了
I've got you now
小心，死胖子
Watch it, Chunky!
真抱歉，条顿市长
你搞什么鸟龙？
- Mayor Tilton, I'm so--
- What's wrong with you?
他就是面具怪客
That man is The Mask
多利安才是
我亲眼看见
No. Dorian Tyrel was The Mask.
I saw it with my own eyes
他是我们的救星
This man here saved our lives
有我相助嘛
你真是英雄
- With a little help.
- You're a real hero
这没什么
It's nothing...
身为铁血美国男儿
any American with...
愿为社会贡献一切
balls of steel wouldn't do
for his community
麦乐，走
Come on
市长，你看到那只狗？
Mayor Tilton, did you see that dog?
你少去惹它
Leave the dog alone
明天一大早找我报到
I want you in my office
first thing tomorrow
是，大人
拍马屁没用啦
- Yes, Your Honor.
- That doesn't sound good at all
是没用，你说什么才有用？
No, it doesn't.
What would sound good to you?
吃早饭
闭嘴
- Breakfast.
- Shut up!
你确定要这样做？
Sure you know what you're doing?
我确定
I'm sure
那就动手吧
Then do what you must
你真的不会怀念他？
Sure you won't miss this guy?
他走了，就只剩下我
When he's gone, all that's left is me
甜到心坎里！
Smoking!